// const dayOneQuestions = [
//   {
//     question: "Which festival is celebrated after the month of fasting?",
//     options: [
//       "Eid-al-Fitr",
//       "Eid-al-Adha",
//       "Birthday of Prophet Muhammad (PBUH)",
//       "There is no festival after the month of fasting",
//     ],
//     correctOption: 0,
//   },
//   {
//     question:
//       "Which night is specified in the Quran as a night greater than 1,000 months?",
//     options: [
//       "Night of Barat (Shab-e-Barat)",
//       "Last night of the month of Ramadhan",
//       "Night of Qadr (Laylat al-Qadr)",
//       "First night of the month of Ramadhan",
//     ],
//     correctOption: 2,
//   },
//   {
//     question: "What is the pre-dawn meal known as?",
//     options: ["Ifthar", "Suhoor", "Valimah", "None of the above"],
//     correctOption: 1,
//   },
//   {
//     question:
//       "How long do Muslims fast every day during the month of Ramadhan?",
//     options: [
//       "Muslims fast from dawn to sunset",
//       "Muslims fast only during the nights",
//       "Muslims fast from afternoon till sunset",
//       "Muslims do not fast during the month of Ramadhan",
//     ],
//     correctOption: 0,
//   },
//   {
//     question: "During which month do Muslims fast for a month?",
//     options: ["Sha’ban", "Ramadhan", "Shawwal", "Rajjab"],
//     correctOption: 1,
//   },
//   {
//     question:
//       "How many days does the month of Ramadhan or Month of Fasting last?",
//     options: [
//       "28 or 29 days",
//       "31 or 32 days",
//       "30 or 31 days",
//       "29 or 30 days",
//     ],
//     correctOption: 3,
//   },
//   {
//     question:
//       "What is the Night Salah (Prayers) during the month of Ramadhan called?",
//     options: [
//       "Ishraq Salah",
//       "Taraweeh Salah",
//       "Fard Salah",
//       "There are no Night Prayers",
//     ],
//     correctOption: 1,
//   },
//   {
//     question: "Who are exempted from fasting during the month of Ramadhan?",
//     options: [
//       "Menstruating women",
//       "People who are travelling",
//       "People who are ill",
//       "All the above",
//     ],
//     correctOption: 3,
//   },
//   {
//     question: "Which Pillar of Islam is Sawm (Fasting)?",
//     options: [
//       "Sawm (Fasting) is the Fifth Pillar of Islam",
//       "Sawm (Fasting) is the First Pillar of Islam",
//       "Sawm (Fasting) is not a Pillar of Islam",
//       "Sawm (Fasting) is the Fourth Pillar of Islam",
//     ],
//     correctOption: 0,
//   },
//   {
//     question:
//       "What is the Obligatory Charity which is paid in the form of people’s staple food or grains before the Eid Prayers?",
//     options: [
//       "Sadaqah",
//       "Amanah",
//       "It is not required to pay charity",
//       "Zakat-al-Fitr",
//     ],
//     correctOption: 3,
//   },
// ];

// export default dayOneQuestions;
const dayOneQuestions = [ 
  {
    question: "What is the name of the city that Shu'aib AS was sent to?",
    options: ["Aad", "Iram", "Madyan", "Makkah"],
    correctOption: 2,
    justification: "And to the people of Madyan We sent their brother Shu'aib. He said, 'O my people! Worship Allah-you have no other god except Him. A clear proof has already come to you from your Lord. So give just measure and weight, do not defraud people of their property, nor spread corruption in the land after it has been set in order. This is for your own good, if you are 'truly' believers.' (Surah al-A'raaf 85)"
  },
  {
    question: "What is the name of the father of Ibraheem AS?",
    options: ["Haroon", "Zakariyyah", "Aazar", "Binyameen"],
    correctOption: 2,
    justification: "And 'remember' when Abraham said to his father, Azar, 'Do you take idols as gods? It is clear to me that you and your people are entirely misguided.' (Surah al-an'aam 74)"
  },
  {
    question: "In the Qur'an, a group of people is described as if they were donkeys carrying books. Who are these people?",
    options: ["Jews", "Christians", "People of Makkah", "Romans"],
    correctOption: 0,
    justification: "The example of those who were entrusted with 'observing' the Torah but failed to do so, is that of a donkey carrying books. How evil is the example of those who reject Allah's signs! For Allah does not guide the wrongdoing people. (Surah Jumu'ah 5)"
  },
  {
    question: "Which prophet was inside the belly of a whale?",
    options: ["Yusuf AS", "Yunus AS", "Ilyaas AS", "Dawud AS"],
    correctOption: 1,
    justification: "And Jonah (Yunus) was indeed one of the messengers. ˹Remember˺ when he fled to the overloaded ship. Then ˹to save it from sinking,˺ he drew straws ˹with other passengers˺. He lost ˹and was thrown overboard˺. Then the whale swallowed him up while he was blameworthy... (Surah As-Saffaath 139-148)"
  },
  {
    question: "What was the advice given by Shu'aib AS to his people as mentioned in the Qur'an?",
    options: ["To not kill people", "To not commit indecent actions", "To measure correctly and fairly when selling", "To be kind to parents"],
    correctOption: 2,
    justification: "Give full measure, and cause no loss ˹to others˺. Weigh with an even balance, and do not defraud people of their property. Nor go about spreading corruption in the land. And fear the One Who created you and ˹all˺ earlier peoples. (Surah Ash-Shu'araa 181-184)"
  },
  {
    question: "Which surah of the Qur'an does not start with Bismillah?",
    options: ["Surah Baqarah", "Surah Al-Anfaal", "Surah At-Tauba", "Surah An-Nisa"],
    correctOption: 2,
    justification: "Surah At-Taubah is the only surah in the Quran that does not begin with 'Bismillah'. (Islamqa.info)"
  },
  {
    question: "Allah inspired the mother of a prophet. Who was this prophet?",
    options: ["Muhammad SAW", "Ibraheem AS", "Musa AS", "Yahya AS"],
    correctOption: 2,
    justification: "We inspired the mother of Moses: 'Nurse him, but when you fear for him, put him then into the river, and do not fear or grieve. We will certainly return him to you, and make him one of the messengers.' (Surah al-Qasas 7)"
  },
  {
    question: "Which prophet was saved from the fire as a miracle?",
    options: ["Dawud AS", "Adam AS", "Jibrael AS", "Ibraheem AS"],
    correctOption: 3,
    justification: "They concluded, 'Burn him up to avenge your gods, if you must act.' We ordered, 'O fire! Be cool and safe for Abraham!' (Surah Anbiyaa 68-70)"
  },
  {
    question: "Which prophet smashed the idols of his people?",
    options: ["Nooh AS", "Hood AS", "Ibrahim AS", "Dawood AS"],
    correctOption: 2,
    justification: "So he smashed them into pieces, except the biggest of them, so they might turn to it ˹for answers˺. (Surah Anbiyaa 58)"
  },
  {
    question: "In the time of Musa AS, which of these punishments were sent to the people of Egypt?",
    options: ["Rats", "Dogs", "Frogs", "Snails"],
    correctOption: 2,
    justification: "So We plagued them with floods, locusts, lice, frogs, and blood—all as clear signs, but they persisted in arrogance and were a wicked people. (Surah A'raaf 132-136)"
  }
];

export default dayOneQuestions;
